now we're going to um look at laying out
the
pallet okay so I like to use a um a
light
palette just so I can see the um the
color mixes more accurately in the in
the lights if you've got a very dark
palette then it's harder to judge judge
your light
mixes and in terms of layout of colors I
like to go from light to
dark from warm into
cool let's just start with
the the white
first put about four or
five inches of paint
out
there
then about an
inch 3 or 4
cm or paint
it's always better to give
yourself lots of
paint rather
than trying to mix up extra Paints in
mid
flow just make sure you've
got
enough and these are cheap paints
anyway doesn't really matter too
much if you um
waste waste these
paints okay
then put
my black
here bur
some
there then
i' like to put a um
gradation the tonal gradation for each
color so I'll just move these out out of
the
way right so you see these colors here
these these are very dark blue purple
and azarin
well I'll get R to that in a
second so if we lighten these colors
it's just
easier to mix them in because if you're
mixing these dark colors into a
light light color there's going to be
too
much
contrast it's more difficult
to
mix a sule
color okay so I like to mix
something so that would be like a dark
blue like to make something
let it looks
like a blue
one so it's like a mid
blue
okay then what I we do with the paint
that's left on the plet
knife mix up a lighter tone
going to do that with all the
colors make
sure all this
paint it's thoroughly mixed
okay the wiping off the pallet
knife don't want to contaminate the next
color so this mid purple I'm looking for
like what looks like a
purple using that
color what's left on the pet
knife to
mix the next
turnone just give
that more of a
mixan the pet
so looking for this
mid
Liz with what's left on
there
knife to mix up
lighter version surprising just how
much how
dark that color is what's left on the
the pallet knife there
sling
go PL
knife some that orange
up light orange
white car
knife
yellow so I Ed so look at the pet knife
that I'm using
there another typical
shape find this is quite is pretty
useful
getting into smaller
areas okay so that's
how I would
mix
prepare the uh the pallet